citavi.com 2017-07-04

# Privacy policy - Citavi Swiss Academic Software

### Swiss Academic Software GmbH

Date of last revision: September 12, 2016

| 

We, Swiss Academic Software GmbH, located at Florhofstrasse 2, 8820 Wädenswil, Switzerland, develop and distribute the Citavi software program and have contact with prospective customers, customers, and users. This privacy policy explains what data we collect and save either directly from you or via a third party and what we do with it.

If you want to view your saved personal data or if you want us to delete your data, please contact us at [support@citavi.com](mailto:support@citavi.com).

The applications and processes that collect data are constantly changing. This privacy policy will be regularly updated to reflect these changes.

If you do not agree to our use of your personal data – for example, after a privacy policy revision – you can send a short email request that your personal data be deleted to [support@citavi.com](mailto:support@citavi.com).   

### Citavi website visits

| 

We statistically evaluate website visits without collecting personally identifiable information. Whenever you visit our website, the following information is automatically transmitted to our web server:

  * IP address
  * Hostname
  * Browser and operating system 
  * Webpage cookies
  * Language
  * Webpages you visited before visiting the website

If JavaScript is enabled, we can also obtain the following information from your browser:

  * Screen resolution
  * Color depth
  * Browser window size
  * Mozilla/Firefox plugins 

We use the open source program Piwik to statistically evaluate website visits. The user information that Piwik collects makes it impossible to personally identify you, since the address of your computer or mobile device is saved anonymously. Our purpose in collecting this information is to improve our website. To this end, we also use cookies. We let you know this in a message displayed at the top of the webpage.

Cookies are small text files that are stored on your computer or mobile device. We can use cookies to determine if your computer or mobile device has already communicated with our webpages, for example. We delete the raw data collected by Piwik every three months.

If you don't want us to collect information about your visits to our website, you can opt out. When you do so, a cookie that prevents Piwik from saving information will be saved in your browser. For technical reasons, this cookie will only work in the browser in which it was orginally saved. If you delete cookies in this browser or use another browser or device, you will need to opt out again. To opt out, clear the checkbox below.

All Piwik cookies start with these characters: __pk_ref_ ,  __pk_cvar_ ,  __pk_id_  und  __pk_ses_. If you opt out, you will see the following cookie:  _piwik_ignore_.

Piwik saves the following information, which is deleted every three months at the latest:

  * The date and time you visited the page
  * The title of the page visited (Page Title)
  * The URL of the page visited (Page URL)
  * The URL of the page that was visited before visiting the current page (Referrer URL)
  * Files you clicked or downloaded (Download)
  * Clicked links that lead to another domain (Outlink)
  * The time the server needed to load the page (Page speed)
  * Your IP address saved in an anonymous format
  * Your location: country, region, city (Geolocation)
  * The time of the visit in your time zone
  * The browser you use (User-Agent)
  * The browser language (Accept-Language)
  * Your screen resolution

### Newsletter subscriptions

| 

We offer you the chance to subscribe to various email newsletters. W use the online service MailChimp for sign up and email delivery. Mailchimp is offered by the company Rocket Science Group located at 675 Ponce de Leon Ave NE, Suite 5000, Atlanta, GA 30308.

If you sign up for a newsletter, your name and email address are saved by MailChimp and used to send the newsletter to the email address you provided. 

In addition, MailChimp also collects the following information: if and when you open a newsletter, if you click the links in a newsletter, your IP address, the browser or email program you are using, and other details of this sort. MailChimp uses clear GIFs (also known as web beacons) in newsletter emails to collect this information.

We can view this information in the online service's interface. You can unsubscribe from a newsletter at any time by clicking the "unsubscribe" link at the bottom of the newsletter.

MailChimp's privacy policy can be found at [http://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/). Although the privacy policy is primarily written for users of the service (us in this case) it also contains important information pertinent to newsletter subscribers.

The servers which MailChimp uses for data storage are located in the United States (see section 14 in MailChimp's privacy policy), so the personal information you provide during sign up is transferred there. In an attempt to have a similar data security level as in Switzerland and the EU, we have signed a data processing agreement with MailChimp that contains the EU's standard contractual clauses (see section 15 in MailChimp's privacy policy).  
  
### Site license statistics

| 

If a university or organization has signed a site license agreement, the contact person will receive a monthly email containing statistics for how many licenses were requested in addition to other news relevant for site license customers.

To send these emails, we use a locally installed computer program. Personal information is only saved on our local network.

Please write to us at [support@citavi.com](mailto:support@citavi.com) if you no longer wish to receive the monthly site license newsletter.  
  
### Forum posts

| 

We provide a moderated, freely accessible forum at [www.citavi.com/forum](https://www.citavi.com/forum). To do so, we use a forum software program that is run on servers located in Germany.

In the forum you can publicly post your question so that either we or other users can answer it. To create a forum post, you first need to register with your name and email address. After that you can sign in with a password.

Your posts will be published in our forum under your user name, which does not need to be your real name. The information you submit during registration and your forum posts are saved indefinitely.

Under certain circumstance we may write to the email address you used to register in order to clarify a question privately rather than publicly in the forum.  
  
### Direct Requests

| 

It's also possible to directly contact us with questions about Citavi. We offer a few different ways to do so: our online form [www.citavi.com/ticket](https://www.citavi.com/ticket), the contact form in your Citavi account and by email.

We save and respond to your questions in our customer support system, which runs on virtual servers located in Germany.

Information is saved indefinitely so that it can be viewed again for follow-up questions or if other users experience similar problems. 

Questions regarding license purchases may be forwarded to our online reseller so that they can contact you.

In addition, your question is saved in our customer database, which is run by Microsoft on severs located in Dublin and Amsterdam.   
  
### Quote requests and  
license purchases  
in Citavi's Online Shop

| 

If you request a quote for a license purchase or if you purchase licenses in our online shop, payment processing and order fulfillment are carried out by the e-commerce provider cleverbridge AG located at Gereonstrasse 43-65, 50670 Cologne, Germany. Cleverbridge AG's privacy policy can be found [here](https://secure.citavi.com/635/?scope=opprivacy) and their general terms and conditions can be found [here](https://secure.citavi.com/635/?scope=optandc).

To request a quote or to place an order, you need to provide the following information:

  * Salutation
  * First and last names
  * Your address
  * Your email address

If you purchase licenses for an organization, you also need to specify the organization's name. You can also enter a billing address that differs from the delivery address.

This information is used as described in cleverbridge AG's privacy policy. Using a software program that cleverbridge AG provides to us, we can view this data. When you complete a purchase you also enter payment information, such as your credit card number or bank details. This information is saved and used by cleverbridge AG as detailed in their privacy policy and cannot be viewed by us.

After completing a purchase with cleverbridge AG, the order details and status are transferred to us and saved in our customer database. Our customer database is run by Microsoft on servers located in Dublin and Amsterdam.

We use the information you provide while placing an order for the following purposes:

  * To create a license key and make it available in an account
  * To clarify questions regarding a quote, a purchase, or your licenses 
  * To inform you of releases of new versions and under what conditions you can upgrade
  * To let you know about special offers on the basis of your existing licenses.

### License purchases from our partners

| 

In several countries we work with partners who distribute Citavi for us. If you purchase a Citavi license from one of these partners, please make yourself familiar with the partner's privacy policy and general terms and conditions of business. 

  * Belgium: RITME, Rue des Anciens Etangs 40,1190 Brussels (Forest), Belgium
  * Austria, Germany, Switzerland: made|for|science GmbH, Varrentrappstasse. 40-42, 60486 Frankfurt am Main, Germany
  * France: RITME, 72, Rue des Archives, 75003 Paris, France 
  * India: DELLSOFT Technologies P. Ltd, WZ-29, FF, Uggarsain Market, Ashok Nagar, New Delhi, 110018, India
  * Switzerland: SCIENTIFIC SOLUTIONS A.A. SA, Rue du Midi 2, 1009 Pully, Switzerland 

Orders placed by our partners are processed by cleverbridge AG located at Gereonstrasse 43-65, 50670 Cologne, Germany. The following information is necessary for license key creation:

  * Organization name
  * Salutation
  * First and last name
  * Address
  * Email address

This information is also transferred to cleverbridge AG.

After the partner completes a purchase with cleverbridge AG, the order details and status are transferred to us and saved in our customer database. Based on this information, we create license keys and make them available in your Citavi account.

We use the information you provide while placing an order for the following purposes:

  * To create your license key and make it available in your account
  * To clarify questions regarding a quote, a purchase, or your licenses 
  * To inform you of releases of new versions and under what conditions you can upgrade
  * To let you know about special offers on the basis of your existing licenses.

### Citavi accounts

| 

Your license key can be accessed in your personal Citavi account. There you can view, change, and delete the personal information you sent to us during a purchase or when requesting a site license. The information is saved in our customer database, which is run by Microsoft on servers located in Dublin and Amsterdam. 

A Citavi account is created under the following circumstances: 

  * When a site license is requested, in order to make the license key available
  * When purchasing licenses in the Citavi Shop or from one of our partners, in order to make the license key available.
  * If you request a lost license key and don't yet have an account, in order to make the license key available.
  * If the license administrator for your organization assigns you a license
  * If you create the account yourself

You can create the account with different information depending on the circumstances:

  * With an email and password
  * By signing in to a Facebook, Google, or Microsoft account
  * By signing in to your university account if your university offers one and if we've enabled this method for your university.

If you don't provide an email address during registration, we will ask you to add it so that we can contact you with questions regarding your licenses or account.

If you sign in to your Citavi account with a Facebook, Google or Microsoft account, the service you're using will request that you allow Citavi access to certain information.

You can view, restrict, or remove app permissions on the following pages:

  * Facebook:   
<https://www.facebook.com/settings?tab=applications>
  * Microsoft:  
<https://account.microsoft.com/privacy> > Manage permissions
  * Google Plus:  
<https://myaccount.google.com/security?pli=1#connectedapps>

### Service or site  
license orders

| 

If you request or order services or site licenses from us, we will send you quotes and invoices created with the online application billomat, which is offered by Billomat GmbH & Co. KG located at Burgschmietstraße 2-4, 90419 Nuremberg, Germany. We save the necessary information in the online application and in our customer database, which is run by Microsoft on servers located in Dublin and Amsterdam.

You can view billomat's privacy policy here: <https://www.billomat.com/en/privacy>  
  
### End user licenses  
under site license agreements

| 

An end user license under a site license agreement can be accessed in your Citavi Account. Your affiliation with the university or organization offering the site license is saved.  
  
### In Citavi

| 

If you have an active Internet connection, Citavi will sometimes attempt to communicate with our servers or the servers of information providers.  
The servers of information providers are contacted for the following reasons:

  * To re-route search queries or RSS requests
  * To download data (especially bibliographic data, library location information, book cover images, or full text). 

Swiss Academic Software's server is contacted for the following reasons: 

  * To check for and download updates to the software.
  * To download citation style or import filter files
  * To download help texts that are displayed in the program
  * To re-route search queries to an information provider and to receive the results from such queries, particularly if a direct connection to the information provider fails. Your search queries and results are only retained for as long as is technically necessary to provide the results to you. They are never permanently saved or used for any other purpose.

We statistically evaluate anonymized server connection information to ensure sufficient infrastructure performance.

When Citavi connects to the Citavi servers, no personally identifiable information is transferred. Project data is only transferred if it is necessary for an online search. For example, the DOI or ISBN number might be sent in order to retrieve the corresponding bibliographic information.  
  
### Bug reports

| 

If you experience a crash, Citavi can sometimes create a bug report for it. You can then review and edit the report and send it to us by email. This information makes us aware of the bug and helps us fix it.

The bug report contains information regarding actions carried out by the program and some basic computer information, such as the Citavi and Word versions that are installed. 

The bug report does not contain any information on the contents of your Citavi projects or any personally identifiable information.  
  
### Activity logs

| 

If you contact us because you are experiencing an error and if we are unable to reproduce the error, we may ask you to send an activity log. The activity log helps us better understand why the error occurred on your computer.

Activity logs contain information on actions in Citavi along with any error messages. They do not contain any information on the contents of your Citavi projects or any personally identifiable information.
